[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
Build a sentiment classifier.
建立情感分析器
And I'm gonna put a # here to make it a nice title.
我要在这里加上一个好一点的标题
So this is our next task here.
这就是我们下一步的任务
And so, when you build a sentiment classifier,
当你在建立情感分析器的时候
you're talking about positives and negatives.
你其实说的是 正面评价 或者负面评价
So, thumbs down, and thumbs up.
也就是 赞 还是踩
But if you remember, our product ratings, we're not about positive and
如果你还记得的话 我们产品的评分 并不是分为正面评价和负面评价
negative, they're numerical things.
而是一些数字
So, for example, if I take all the products, and
举个例子 当我把这些产品
I'll take the rating column and I do a .show, and we did above just for
评分这一列 进行排序 再显示 (输入product['rating].show这行代码)
the giraffe, but do a .show for everything with the view equal
但是我们希望显示的评价 是分类性质的数据 所以 (view='Categorical')
to Categorical, we're now getting a histogram for
这样我们就得到了一张评价的图表
all of the views, and if you take a quick look at it, you'll see that most reviews
先简单浏览一下所有评价 你会发现大部分评价
are positive across the board 107,000 reviews are five stars.
都是正评价 大约107000条点评都是五星好评
So most people review positively, and just write reviews about products they like.
所以说大部分人都给出了正评价 写下了他们为什么喜欢这款产品
They don't typically write reviews about products they don't like.
人们往往不会写为什么不喜欢某款产品
Then the next set of reviews, 33,000 four stars.
剩下的一组点评就是大约33000条四星评价
Then 3 stars and again, a lot of people write really bad reviews 1 star, 2 star,
然后就是三星评价 也有不少人写下了一些特别负面的评价 也就是给出了一星和两星
why would you give a review product 2 stars?
想想为什么人们会给出两星这个评价呢?
You might as well just give them 1 star if you really hated it.
如果你真的讨厌某个产品  你也就直接给出一星差评了
And this is what we observe in the histogram.
这是我们从图表中观察到的
But again, for sentiment analysis, we have to define what's thumbs up and
对于情感分析来说 我们要知道的是正评价和
what's thumbs down.
负评价
And so I'm gonna make an arbitrary choice here.
让我们先做个随性的选择吧
Let's say that things that 4, 5 stars are things that people liked.
假设四星和五星代表着人们喜欢这个产品
So those are positives.
所以他们是正评价
Things that 1 and 2 stars are negative.
一星评价和二星评价是负面评价
But the things that are 3 stars, those are kind of in the middle.
但是对于三星的评价 还蛮难抉择的 因为他们处于正负之间
So, let's just throw those out.
我们先放任不管
So we're gonna do a little bit of what we'll call data engineering,
我们现在要做的是所谓的数据工程
just defining what is a positive and negative sentiment.
也就是定义 什么是正面情感 什么是负面情感
So let's do that right now.
让我们现在来做
So in the subsection we're gonna define
在接下来的部分中我们将要定义
what's a positive and a negative sentiment.
什么是正面情感 什么是负面情感
And what I'm gonna
我将要做的是
do first is ignore all
先忽略
city star reviews.
三星的评价
The way to do it is by saying,
如何做到呢?
okay I'm gonna take the product stable the variable products.
我们现在产品中选择
And I'm gonna just select everything out
我会在产品中选择所有 但是不包括
of the products table whose rating was not 3.
那些评分为三星的产品
So, products[products['rating'] |= 3].
所以代码是这样的 products=products[products['rating']!=3]
So that was our first step in our little data engineering task.
这就是我们数据工程中的第一步
And now, the next step in this task
下一步的任务就是
is to actually find what stems up and stems down.
去找到那些正评价 或者负评价
So I'm gonna say a positive
所以 我会定义那些正面情感
sentiment equals 4 star or
是四星或者
5 star reviews.
五星评价
So let's go ahead and
然后让我们继续
add a new column to our table that defines the actual sentiment.
在我们的列表中添加一列 这一列会定义真正的情感
So products new column called sentiment.
所以product 新的一列会叫做情感 (sentiment)
It's gonna be a binary column, zero one.
这会是一个二进制列 里面是0或者1
And, the way we're gonna define the column, is we're gonna say,
我们要定义的这一列 就是我们所说的
of the products rating, is it greater equal to 4?
产品评分 它是否大于4
If it's greater or equal to 4, it's gonna get a 1, and
如果它大于4 那么情感这一列就是1
if it's less than 4, it's gonna get a 0, and
如果小于4 就是0
so now if I take another look at my product stable, so head
如果你看我们产品表格的标头
You should see that I've added a new column on the right called Sentiment.
你会发现我们在右边有新的一列 叫做情感 (sentiment)
And most of the sentiments are positive, as we saw earlier, but
大部分时候情感是正向的 就像我们之前看到的那样
many are negative, zero.
但还有一些负面的 也就是情感这一列的值为0
Okay, now we're ready, we're finally
现在我们终于
ready to train our sentiment classifier.
可以去训练我们的情感分析器了
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community